<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2025-12-31T09:45:12+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2025. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251230204253624.2</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Periods of heavy rain, and amounts may approach warning criteria, or possibly exceed them in localised areas. Thunderstorms possible (moderate risk) with rainfall rates up to 25 mm/h. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Moderate. Changes: The Watch now covers all of Buller District and has been extended to 3pm Thursday.</summary>
    <updated>2025-12-31T09:42:53+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-12-31T09:42:53+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251230204253624.2"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251230204253624.1</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Periods of heavy rain, and amounts may approach warning criteria. Thunderstorms possible (moderate risk from afternoon onwards) with rainfall rates up to 25 mm/h. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Moderate. Changes: Watch extended to 9am Thursday.</summary>
    <updated>2025-12-31T09:42:53+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-12-31T09:42:53+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251230204253624.1"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251230204253624.3</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 100 to 130 mm of rain. Peak rates of 10 to 20 mm/h. Thunderstorms possible (moderate risk from afternoon onwards) which could see rainfall rates up to 25 mm/h. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Minimal.</summary>
    <updated>2025-12-31T09:42:53+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-12-31T09:42:53+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251230204253624.3"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251230204512139.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Conditions are favourable for development of heavy showers and thunderstorms this afternoon and evening. Some of these thunderstorms may become SEVERE, producing downpours of 25 to 40 mm/h. Thunderstorms are expected to ease tonight. Rainfall of this intensity can cause surface and/or flash flooding, especially about low-lying areas such as streams, rivers or narrow valleys, and may also lead to slips. 
Driving conditions will also be hazardous with surface flooding and poor visibility in heavy rain. 

</summary>
    <updated>2025-12-31T09:45:12+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-12-31T09:45:12+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251230204512139.0"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
