<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2026. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260213181623448.5</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Heavy rain is expected from Sunday morning, especially about the Wairoa District. There is a high chance a warning will be issued for at least some of the area on Sunday. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: High. Changes: Watch period now covers Sunday only.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260213181623448.5"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260213181623448.7</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 100 to 120 mm of rain. Intensities of 15 to 20 mm per hour are possible. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Low.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260213181623448.7"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260213181623448.8</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 100 to 150 mm of rain on top of what has already fallen. Intensities of 15 to 25 mm per hour are possible, but may reach 25 to 40 mm per hour in downpours during Saturday which may be accompanied by thunderstorms. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Moderate.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260213181623448.8"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260213181623448.9</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 70 to 100 mm of rain on top of what has already fallen. Intensities of 20 to 25 mm per hour, but possibly 25 to 40 mm per hour in localised downpours which may be accompanied by thunderstorms. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Low.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260213181623448.9"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260213181623448.6</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Periods of heavy rain, with a chance of thunderstorms and localised downpours of 25 to 40 mm per hour. Severe Thunderstorm Warnings may be issued for localised storms, and rainfall accumulations may exceed warning criteria in some regions. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Moderate.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-14T07:16:23+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260213181623448.6"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
