<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2025-12-11T16:06:54+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2025. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.ot.20251211023041336.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 03:22 pm, MetService weather radar detected severe thunderstorms near MIDDLEMARCH, LAKE MAHINERANGI, CLARKS JUNCTION, SUTTON and THE LAMMERLAW RANGE.

These severe thunderstorms are moving towards the east, and are expected to lie near CLARKS JUNCTION, HUMMOCK (BETWEEN MIDDLEMARCH AND WAIKOUAITI) and HINDON at 03:52 pm and near DUNEDIN, WAIKOUAITI, OUTRAM, WARRINGTON and HINDON at 04:22 pm.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by torrential rain and large hail.

Impact:

Torrential rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.

Large hail can cause significant damage to crops, orchards, vines, glasshouses and vehicles, and make driving conditions hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2025-12-11T15:30:41+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-12-11T15:30:41+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.ot.20251211023041336.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251211030654924.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Slow-moving isolated thunderstorms are expected through inland parts of Rotorua, Bay of Plenty, Gisborne/Tairawhiti and Hawke's Bay, also Taupo this afternoon and evening.

For the very far southeast of Waikato, inland Bay of Plenty and Rotorua, Taupo north and east of the city and the ranges of Hawke's Bay about and north of SH5 and the far southwest of Gisborne/Tairawhiti, a few of these thunderstorms may be severe between 4pm and 10pm today (Thursday) with localised downpours of 25-40mm.</summary>
    <updated>2025-12-11T16:06:54+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-12-11T16:06:54+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251211030654924.0"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
