<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2025-11-09T16:12:36+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2025. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251108202345585.1</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>A period of heavy rain with possible thunderstorms. Amounts may approach warning criteria. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Moderate.</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-09T09:23:45+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-09T09:23:45+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251108202345585.1"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.ak.20251109023610534.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 03:22 pm, MetService weather radar detected severe thunderstorms near HUNUA and THE HUNUA RANGES.

These severe thunderstorms are moving towards the southeast, and are expected to lie near HUNUA, THE HUNUA RANGES and ARARIMU at 03:52 pm and near KAIAUA, HUNUA, MANGATAWHIRI, THE HUNUA RANGES and ARARIMU at 04:22 pm.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by very heavy rain.

Impact:

Very heavy rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-09T15:36:10+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-09T15:36:10+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.ak.20251109023610534.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251109024119282.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>A warm moist air-mass and daytime heating are likely to generate heavy showers and thunderstorms over inland parts the upper North Island this afternoon and evening. For inland parts of Northland, Auckland, the far south of Coromandel Peninsula, the far west of the Bay of Plenty and the northwest corner of Waikato. there is a moderate risk of SEVERE thunderstorms with localised downpours of 25 to 40 mm/h between 3 and 9pm today. Rainfall of this intensity can cause surface and/or flash flooding, especially about low-lying areas such as streams, rivers or narrow valleys, and may also lead to slips. 
Driving conditions will also be hazardous with surface flooding and poor visibility in heavy rain. 
</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-09T15:41:19+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-09T15:41:19+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251109024119282.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.nl.20251109031236725.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 04:00 pm, MetService weather radar detected a line of severe thunderstorms lying from MANGAMUKA to MOENGAWAHINE to MAUNGATUROTO.

This line of severe thunderstorms is moving towards the southwest, and is expected to lie from MANGAMUKA to MOENGAWAHINE to PAPAROA at 04:30 pm and from MANGAMUKA to MOENGAWAHINE to PAPAROA at 05:00 pm.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by very heavy rain.

Impact:

Very heavy rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-09T16:12:36+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-09T16:12:36+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.nl.20251109031236725.0"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
