<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2025-11-08T19:42:40+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2025. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251107181530994.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>A warm moist air-mass and daytime heating are likely to generate heavy showers over Auckland and Northland today. For inland and western Northland, and Auckland about the Kaipara Harbour there is a moderate risk of SEVERE thunderstorms with downpours, 24 to 40 mm/h. These storms are capable of producing marble sized hail and flooding rainfall. 

Rainfall of this intensity can cause surface and/or flash flooding, especially about low-lying areas such as streams, rivers or narrow valleys, and may also lead to slips. 
Driving conditions will also be hazardous with surface flooding and poor visibility in heavy rain. 
</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-08T07:15:30+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-08T07:15:30+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251107181530994.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.nl.20251108062522457.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 07:15 pm, MetService weather radar detected a line of severe thunderstorms lying from KERIKERI to NGAWHA SPRINGS.

This line of severe thunderstorms is moving towards the eastsoutheast, and is expected to lie from KERIKERI to MOEREWA to NGAWHA SPRINGS at 07:45 pm and from PURERUA to MOEREWA to OPAHI at 08:15 pm.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by torrential rain.

Impact:

Torrential rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-08T19:25:22+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-08T19:25:22+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.nl.20251108062522457.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251108064240674.1</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>A period of heavy rain with possible thunderstorms. Amounts may approach warning criteria. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Moderate.</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-08T19:42:40+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-08T19:42:40+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251108064240674.1"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251108064240674.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>A period of heavy rain, and amounts may approach warning criteria. Thunderstorms possible Monday morning. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Low.</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-08T19:42:40+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-08T19:42:40+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251108064240674.0"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
