<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2026-02-13T16:30:16+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2026. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.1</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Periods of heavy rain with a chance of thunderstorms until early Saturday morning. Localised downpours of 25 to 40 mm per hour are possible, especially inland. More widespread heavy rain is expected from Saturday evening, especially about the Wairoa District. There is a high chance a warning will be issued for at least some of the area for late Saturday and into Sunday. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: High. Changes: Period extended and chance of upgrade increased to high.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.1"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.4</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 100 to 120 mm of rain. Intensities of 15 to 20 mm per hour are possible. Some localised heavy rain is possible from this evening before the warning begins, but the threat of widespread warning amounts of rain starts late Saturday morning. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Low. Changes: Upgraded to Warning (Orange) and period changed.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.4"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.5</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 150 to 200 mm of rain, with possibly 250 mm in localised areas if downpours occur. Intensities of 20 to 25 mm per hour are possible tonight and during Saturday, but may reach 25 to 40 mm per hour in downpours which may be accompanied by thunderstorms. Intensities are likely to be lower during Sunday morning. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Moderate. Changes: Warning period extended and chance of upgrade increased to moderate.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.5"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.6</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 150 to 200 mm of rain. Intensities of 20 to 25 mm per hour, but possibly 25 to 40 mm per hour in localised downpours which may be accompanied by thunderstorms. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Low.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.6"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.7</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 100 to 150 mm of rain, with the chance of 200 mm in localised areas if downpours occur. Intensities of 15 to 25 mm per hour, but there is the chance of thunderstorms with downpours of 25 to 40 mm per hour. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Low. Changes: Upgraded to Warning (Orange).</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.7"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.8</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 120 to 150 mm of rain, with the chance of 200 mm in localised areas if downpours occur. Intensities of 20 to 25 mm per hour are likely, but there is the chance of downpours with 25 to 40 mm per hour. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Moderate. Changes: Upgraded to warning (Orange).</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.8"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.3</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Periods of heavy rain spreading south, with a chance of thunderstorms and localised downpours of 25 to 40 mm per hour. Severe Thunderstorm Warnings may be issued for localised storms, and rainfall accumulations may exceed warning criteria in some regions. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Moderate. Changes: Period extended.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.3"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.2</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Periods of heavy rain with a chance of thunderstorms and localised downpours of 25 to 40 mm per hour. Rainfall accumulations may exceed warning criteria in a few locations. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Moderate. Changes: Period extended.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.2"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Periods of heavy rain with a chance of thunderstorms and localised downpours of 25 to 40 mm per hour, especially inland. Rainfall accumulations may exceed warning criteria in a few locations. Note, further heavy rain possible from Sunday, especially about the Tararua District. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Moderate.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T09:52:20+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260212205220134.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.ak.20260213031526135.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 04:07 pm, MetService weather radar detected a line of severe thunderstorms lying from MOKOHINAU ISLANDS to GREAT BARRIER ISLAND.

This line of severe thunderstorms is moving towards the southeast, and is expected to lie from LITTLE BARRIER ISLAND to GREAT BARRIER ISLAND at 04:37 pm and from LITTLE BARRIER ISLAND to GREAT BARRIER ISLAND at 05:07 pm.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by very heavy rain.

Impact:

Very heavy rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T16:15:26+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T16:15:26+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.ak.20260213031526135.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.bp.20260213033016207.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 04:22 pm, MetService weather radar detected a line of severe thunderstorms lying from OTOROHANGA to WAIPAPA to ATIAMURI.

This line of severe thunderstorms is moving towards the southeast, and is expected to lie from PAEWHENUA to MANGAKINO to ORAKEI KORAKO at 04:52 pm and from WAIPA VALLEY to WHAKAMARU to WAIRAKEI at 05:22 pm.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by very heavy rain.

Impact:

Very heavy rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2026-02-13T16:30:16+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-02-13T16:30:16+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.bp.20260213033016207.0"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
