<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2026-01-02T16:34:31+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2026. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260101201756324.1</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 100 to 150 mm of rain. Peak rates of 25 to  40 mm/h Saturday when thunderstorms could bring localised downpours. Peak rates of 15 to 25 mm/h after midnight on Saturday. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Low. Changes: Watch upgraded to an Orange Warning.</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-02T09:17:56+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-02T09:17:56+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260101201756324.1"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260101201756324.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 70 to 100 mm of rain. Peak rates generally 15 to 25 mm/h. Note that thunderstorms may bring localised downpours north of Napier with rainfall rates of 25 to 40 mm/h. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Minimal. Changes: Watch upgraded to an Orange Warning.</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-02T09:17:56+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-02T09:17:56+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260101201756324.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20260101213246468.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Afternoon and early evening heating and wind convergence bring a moderate risk of thunderstorms to Northland and Auckland, as well as an associated moderate risk of LOCALISED DOWNPOURS of 25 to 40 mm/h. Rainfall of this intensity can cause surface and/or flash flooding, especially about low-lying areas such as streams, rivers or narrow valleys, and may also lead to slips. 
</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-02T10:32:46+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-02T10:32:46+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20260101213246468.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.nl.20260102033431771.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 04:22 pm, MetService weather radar detected severe thunderstorms near WAIOTIRA, TAIPUHA, WAIKIEKIE, MAUNGATAPERE, PURUA and MAUNGAKARAMEA.

These severe thunderstorms are moving towards the southeast, and are expected to lie near MAUNGATUROTO, PAPAROA, BRYNDERWYN, TAIPUHA, WHANGAREI, WAIPU, RUAKAKA and PORTLAND at 04:52 pm and near MAUNGATUROTO, KAIWAKA, PAPAROA, BRYNDERWYN, WAIPU, MANGAWHAI, RUAKAKA, WAIPU COVE and MARSDEN POINT at 05:22 pm.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by very heavy rain.

Impact:

Very heavy rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-02T16:34:31+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-02T16:34:31+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.nl.20260102033431771.0"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
