<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2026-01-03T09:39:12+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2026. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260102203912790.2</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 110 to 170 mm of rain, especially in the ranges. Peak rates of 15 to 25 mm/h, but 25 to 40 mm/h in possible localised downpours from this afternoon through to early Sunday morning, with thunderstorms also possible. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Low.</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-03T09:39:12+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-03T09:39:12+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260102203912790.2"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260102203912790.1</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 90 to 140 mm of rain, especially in the ranges, but 170 mm possible in the Wairoa District. Peak rates of 15 to 25 mm/h, but 25 to 40 mm/h in possible localised downpours. Thunderstorms expected today and will increase the risk of downpours.  Note, heavy rain easing south of the Wairoa District late this evening. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Low. Changes: Warning period extended for the Wairoa District and risk of upgrade increased from minimal to low - mainly for the Wairoa District.</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-03T09:39:12+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-03T09:39:12+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260102203912790.1"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
