<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2025-12-16T16:43:05+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2025. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251215192648518.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Thunderstorms are expected in many regions of the South Island today, bringing the risk of localised heavy rain of 10 to 25 mm/h, and hail 5 to 20 mm in diameter.
In the east of the South Island, about the Canterbury plains and foothills about and south of Rakaia, through eastern Otago to Clutha, there is a moderate risk SEVERE THUNDERSTORMS could develop from early afternoon, producing large hail greater than 20 mm in diameter, or large accumulations of hail.

Large hail can cause significant damage to crops, orchards, vines, glasshouses and vehicles, as well as make driving conditions hazardous. 


</summary>
    <updated>2025-12-16T08:26:48+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-12-16T08:26:48+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251215192648518.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251216003135195.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>A period of heavy rain, and amounts may approach warning criteria, or possibly reach warning criteria on some of the higher peaks. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Moderate.</summary>
    <updated>2025-12-16T13:31:35+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-12-16T13:31:35+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251216003135195.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.ch.20251216031508775.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 04:07 pm, MetService weather radar detected severe thunderstorms near ASHBURTON, LONGBEACH and THE ASHBURTON RIVER MOUTH.

These severe thunderstorms are moving towards the eastnortheast, and are expected to lie near THE ASHBURTON RIVER MOUTH and SEAFIELD at 04:37 pm and near OFFSHORE RAKAIA RIVER MOUTH at 05:07 pm.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by very heavy rain and large hail.

Impact:

Very heavy rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.

Large hail can cause significant damage to crops, orchards, vines, glasshouses and vehicles, and make driving conditions hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2025-12-16T16:15:08+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-12-16T16:15:08+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.ch.20251216031508775.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.ot.20251216034305526.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 04:30 pm, MetService weather radar detected severe thunderstorms near MIDDLEMARCH, CLARKS JUNCTION and SUTTON.

These severe thunderstorms are moving towards the eastsoutheast, and are expected to lie near MIDDLEMARCH, CLARKS JUNCTION and SUTTON at 05:00 pm and near MIDDLEMARCH, HUMMOCK (BETWEEN MIDDLEMARCH AND WAIKOUAITI) and HINDON at 05:30 pm.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by very heavy rain and large hail.

Impact:

Very heavy rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.

Large hail can cause significant damage to crops, orchards, vines, glasshouses and vehicles, and make driving conditions hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2025-12-16T16:43:05+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-12-16T16:43:05+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.ot.20251216034305526.0"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
