<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2025-11-14T14:26:08+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2025. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251113204037725.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Scattered heavy showers and thunderstorms are likely this afternoon and early evening. Some of these thunderstorms may become SEVERE, producing localised downpours of 25 to 40 mm/h or large hail with diameter in excess of 2cm. Expect thunderstorm activity to ease tonight. Rainfall of this intensity can cause surface and/or flash flooding, especially about low-lying areas such as streams, rivers or narrow valleys, and may also lead to slips. Large hail can cause significant damage to crops, orchards, vines, glasshouses and vehicles, as well as make driving conditions hazardous. 


</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-14T09:40:37+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-14T09:40:37+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251113204037725.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Road Snowfall Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.roadsnow.crownrangeroad.20251113221824304.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Brief snow is possible above 800 metres late Friday afternoon. A few snow showers are likely to follow during Saturday morning. Little, if any, snow is expected to settle on the road at these times.</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-14T11:18:24+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-14T11:18:24+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.roadsnow.crownrangeroad.20251113221824304.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Road Snowfall Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.roadsnow.milfordroad.20251113221824269.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Rain may briefly turn to snow about Homer Tunnel during Friday afternoon but little (if any) is expected to settle on the road. Snow showers are expected to follow later on Friday. 1 to 2cm could settle on the road above 800 metres between 10pm Friday and 7am Saturday.</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-14T11:18:24+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-14T11:18:24+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.roadsnow.milfordroad.20251113221824269.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.mh.20251114012608237.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 02:15 pm, MetService weather radar detected severe thunderstorms near TIKOKINO, BRIDGE PA, MARAEKAKAHO, PAKIPAKI, TE HAUKE, PUKEHOU, POUKAWA and GWAVAS.

These severe thunderstorms are moving towards the eastsoutheast, and are expected to lie near HASTINGS, BRIDGE PA, MARAEKAKAHO, PAKIPAKI, TE HAUKE, PUKEHOU and POUKAWA at 02:45 pm and near HASTINGS, HAVELOCK NORTH, BRIDGE PA, MARAEKAKAHO, PAKIPAKI, TE HAUKE and POUKAWA at 03:15 pm.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by torrential rain and hail.

Impact:

Torrential rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.

Hail can cause damage to crops, orchards and vines and may make driving conditions hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2025-11-14T14:26:08+13:00</updated>
    <published>2025-11-14T14:26:08+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.mh.20251114012608237.0"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
