<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2026-01-16T03:59:59+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2026. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Warning - Orange</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260115074412553.9</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Expect 80 to 110 mm of rain in parts of the area on top of what has already fallen. Peaks rates of 25 to 40 mm/h likely in localised downpours, with thunderstorms also possible. Rain easing from the west Friday morning. Impact: Streams and rivers may rise rapidly. Surface flooding, slips, and difficult driving conditions possible. Chance of upgrading to a Red Warning: Low.</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-15T20:44:12+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-15T20:44:12+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260115074412553.9"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260115074412553.5</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Periods of heavy rain, and amounts may approach warning criteria. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Low. Changes: The chance of upgrade for this Watch has been decreased to Low.</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-15T20:44:12+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-15T20:44:12+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20260115074412553.5"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20260115130005293.2</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>A moist unstable northwesterly flow is expected to bring frequent showers and possible thunderstorms to Waikato, Waitomo, Taumarunui and Taupo before dawn. There is a moderate risk of Severe Thunderstorms with downpours bringing localised rainfall rates of 25 to 40 mm/h.

Rainfall of this intensity can cause surface and/or flash flooding, especially about low-lying areas such as streams, rivers or narrow valleys, and may also lead to slips. </summary>
    <updated>2026-01-16T02:00:05+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-16T02:00:05+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20260115130005293.2"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20260115130005293.1</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>A moist unstable northwesterly flow is expected to bring frequent showers and possible thunderstorms to Great Barrier Island and Coromandel Peninsula before dawn. There is a moderate risk of Severe Thunderstorms with downpours bringing localised rainfall rates of 25 to 40 mm/h.

Rainfall of this intensity can cause surface and/or flash flooding, especially about low-lying areas such as streams, rivers or narrow valleys, and may also lead to slips. 
</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-16T02:00:05+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-16T02:00:05+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20260115130005293.1"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20260115130005293.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>A moist unstable northwesterly flow is expected to bring frequent showers and possible thunderstorms to Gisborne/Tairawhiti and the Wairoa District during this morning. There is a moderate risk of Severe Thunderstorms with downpours bringing localised rainfall rates of 25 to 40 mm/h.

Rainfall of this intensity can cause surface and/or flash flooding, especially about low-lying areas such as streams, rivers or narrow valleys, and may also lead to slips. 
</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-16T02:00:05+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-16T02:00:05+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20260115130005293.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Warning</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.bp.20260115145959355.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>At 03:45 am, MetService weather radar detected severe thunderstorms near TE AROHA, MORRINSVILLE, WAITOA, WAIHOU, SPRINGDALE, MARAMARUA and WAERENGA.

These severe thunderstorms are moving towards the southeast, and are expected to lie near MATAMATA, WAHAROA, NGARUA, THE KAIMAI RANGES, SHAFTESBURY, TAHUNA, PATETONGA, TAUHEI and HOE-O-TAINUI at 04:15 am and near MATAMATA, WAHAROA, THE SOUTHERN KAIMAI RANGES, TE POI, THE KAIMAI RANGES, HINUERA, MORRINSVILLE, TE MIRO, NGARUA and KIWITAHI at 04:45 am.

These thunderstorms are expected to be accompanied by very heavy rain.

Impact:

Very heavy rain can cause surface and/or flash flooding about streams, gullies and urban areas, and make driving conditions extremely hazardous.</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-16T03:59:59+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-16T03:59:59+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswarning.bp.20260115145959355.0"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
