<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/atom</id>
  <link href="https://metservice.com"/>
  <updated>2026-01-01T10:45:45+13:00</updated>
  <title>Current Watches, Warnings and Advisories for New Zealand issued by MetService</title>
  <rights>Copyright Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited, 2026. Licensed under Creative Commons BY 4.0.</rights>
  <entry>
    <title>Severe Thunderstorm Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251231200745475.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>An unstable airmass affects the South Island this afternoon and evening. For the Canterbury High Country and foothills south of Arthur's Pass, Central Otago, the Queenstown Lakes District, far inland areas of Southland and inland Fiordland, there is a moderate risk of thunderstorms. There is also a moderate risk that some of these storms may become SEVERE until 10pm today, which could produce localised downpours of 25 to 40 mm/h.
Rainfall of this intensity can cause surface and/or flash flooding, especially about low-lying areas such as streams, rivers or narrow valleys, and may also lead to slips. 
Driving conditions will also be hazardous with surface flooding and poor visibility in heavy rain. 
 </summary>
    <updated>2026-01-01T09:07:45+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-01T09:07:45+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.tswatch.nz.20251231200745475.0"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Heavy Rain Watch</title>
    <id>2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251231214545878.0</id>
    <category term="Met" />
    <summary>Periods of heavy rain, with thunderstorms possible. Amounts may approach warning criteria. If thunderstorms do occur they may bring localised downpours with rainfall intensities of 25 to 40 mm per hour. Chance of upgrading to a Warning: Moderate.</summary>
    <updated>2026-01-01T10:45:45+13:00</updated>
    <published>2026-01-01T10:45:45+13:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Meteorological Service of New Zealand Limited</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="related" type="application/cap+xml" href="https://alerts.metservice.com/cap/alert?id=2.49.0.0.554.0.severeweather.nz.20251231214545878.0"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
